<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Code</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thoughts on Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:46:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m back: The return of the grumpy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/nonsensical-ramblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:46:35 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2025/nonsensical-ramblings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long time no see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, have a seat, and let me ramble about a bunch of things in this long and nonsensical rant. I hope this will be as interesting to you, the reader, as it is to me, the tired programmer in need of venting out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Math behind FP: The Monads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/Understanding-the-math-behind-fp-monads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 15:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/Understanding-the-math-behind-fp-monads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On my &lt;a href=&#34;http://hkupty.github.io/2016/Functional-Programming-Concepts-Idioms-and-Philosophy/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I talked a little about Functional Programming, hoping to introduce it to newcomers and developers with no previous FP experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several people said it was not very precise and it didn&amp;rsquo;t explained some concepts (such as Monads or Functors) with the required level of details.
Well, I do hope to achieve some detailing with this post. Nonetheless, I&amp;rsquo;ll still try to keep it light to those who never programmed functionally before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming: Concepts, Idioms and Philosophy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/Functional-Programming-Concepts-Idioms-and-Philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 10:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/Functional-Programming-Concepts-Idioms-and-Philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_programming&#34;&gt;Functional Programming&lt;/a&gt; has risen as a solution to most modern days problems, such as concurrency and scaling. For some, it is a mystique concept that applies only to Erlang, Haskell and other strange languages that are either too complicated or irrelevant. This is simply not true, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to show how to apply some functional programming concepts on non-functional languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll deconstruct the functional paradigm by first defining what &amp;lsquo;Functional Programming&amp;rsquo; really means, then explaining common idioms and comparing the syntax.
In the end, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to make relevant changes to non-functional in order to follow the Functional Programming Philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Neovim Approach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/A-Neovim-Approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/A-Neovim-Approach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Still on the topic of Neovim taking over tmux&amp;rsquo;s place, and as a response to several interesting comments I&amp;rsquo;ve read on hackernews and reddit regarding &lt;a href=&#34;http://hkupty.github.io/2016/Ditching-TMUX/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d like to show a new approach to what has been discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-not-emacs&#34;&gt;Why not Emacs?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all due respect to Emacs, it is simply a matter of personal taste. I won&amp;rsquo;t start a flamewar here; on the contrary. I do enforce people to try Emacs, as it is a very personal aspect of how you feel confortable to interact with code, scripts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ditching TMUX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/Ditching-TMUX/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 10:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/Ditching-TMUX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I started an experiment. I wanted to know whether I would be able to completely ditch tmux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong here, I absolutely love how tmux makes terminal multiplexing transparent for me. I&amp;rsquo;m also very used to &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;C-b&amp;gt;c&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;C-b&amp;gt;1-0&lt;/code&gt; and so on. I also have a custom set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hkupty/dotfiles/blob/master/tmux/.tmux.conf&#34;&gt;keymaps and plugins&lt;/a&gt; I use frequently, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tmux-plugins/tmux-copycat&#34;&gt;tmux-copycat&lt;/a&gt;, which helps me find paths or urls on the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, I found that my workflow was not optimal, a certain day, where I was constantly switching tabs on neovim and panes on tmux. This was unlikely the best scenario and I challenged me to overcome this by runnig neovim &lt;em&gt;as my terminal multiplexer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initial Commit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/Initial-Commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 09:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/Initial-Commit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all, I&amp;rsquo;m starting this blog so I can speak a little about what moves me and why do I code. As of now, I have 10 years straight of development experience and probably its time for me to start writting down some things I learned through the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can imagine I&amp;rsquo;ll spend a fair amount of time quoting books here. Also, I plan to write a bit about open source projects I use and my view on them. Lastly, I&amp;rsquo;ll surely want to put some code here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
